这里空气可供呼吸
The atmosphere is breathable.
布卡坦没错 曼达洛星没遭到诅咒
Bo-Katan was right. Mandalore is not cursed.
(前情提要)
布卡坦奎兹要出去 把其他流亡的曼达洛人带过来
Bo-Katan Kryze is going off to bring other Mandalorians in exile to us
让我们同胞再次团结
so that we may join together once again.
收复曼达洛星的时间到了
It is time to retake Mandalore.
你来加入佣兵吗
Have you come back to join the mercenaries?
我来收回我的舰队
I've come to reclaim my fleet.
我们曼达洛人不该再自相残杀了
Enough Mandalorian blood has been spilled by our own hands.
曼达洛统治者必须持有黑剑
The ruler of Mandalore must possess the Darksaber.
我在探索曼达洛星时被抓住
While exploring Mandalore, I was captured.
这把剑也被抢走
And this blade was taken from me.
布卡坦救了我并且宰了抓捕者
Bo-Katan rescued me and slayed my captor.
我在此把剑物归原主
I return this blade to its rightful owner.
我发现废弃的新共和国穿梭机
I found a derelict New Republic shuttle.
这是劫囚
This was an extraction.
时间符合吉迪恩星区长的囚船
Flight times match the ship transporting Moff Gideon.
我就知道 他没去受审
I knew it. He never made it to trial.
似乎有什么东西卡在舱壁
There appears to be something embedded in the cabin wall.
那是贝斯卡合金的碎片
It's a fragment of beskar alloy.
拜托 你陷害我
Please. You set me up.
代码TK2755
Code T-K-2-7-5-5.
报告 简短些 我赶时间
Report. And make it quick, as I am short on time.
长官 海盗在内瓦罗星遇到麻烦
Sir, I'm afraid the pirates have run into trouble on Nevarro.
你上次的报告
In your last report,
不是说新共和国不会派人去支援吗
didn't you suggest that the New Republic would not be sending support?
不是新共和国
It wasn't the New Republic.
卡加太守有一群曼达洛人相助
Magistrate Karga was aided by Mandalorians.
哪些曼达洛人
Which Mandalorians?
根据新共和国收到的报告
According to the reports received by the New Republic,
布卡坦奎兹带领一队曼达洛人
Bo-Katan Kryze lead a squadron of Mandalorians
连同丁贾林和那群躲藏的同党
alongside Din Djarin and his covert.
不可能 这两派人是死对头
This cannot be. Those two factions are sworn enemies.
所以我才急忙联络你
Which is why I contacted you with haste.
你的任务别停
Continue with your mission.
我来处理那些曼达洛人
I shall deal with our Mandalorian friends.
新共和国很脆弱
The New Republic is vulnerable,
但我们必须谨慎 别显露出实力
but we must be cautious and show no sign of our true strength.
你说得倒轻松 舰长
Easy for you to say, Captain.
劫掠超太空通道可以赚到不少钱
There's a fortune to be had plundering the hyperspace lanes.
指挥官 你的打带跑行动太引人注目
Commander, your hit-and-run operations are gaining too much notice.
如果别人发觉我们不只是 一群无组织的余党军阀
If we are perceived as anything other than a group of unorganized remnant warlords,
新共和国会更着力追捕我们
the New Republic will increase their efforts to hunt us down.
银河各星球都有忠于帝国的人民
There are citizens loyal to the Empire on every planet in this galaxy.
他们已经开始厌倦了新共和国
They're already getting sick of this New Republic
和那些规章制度
and its rules and regulations.
只要展现力量 他们将再度支持我们
And if we give them a show of strength, they will rally behind us.
没错
Yes.
但这股力量不能浪费
But that strength must not be wasted.
索龙元帅的归来
Grand Admiral Thrawn's return
将会宣告我军的正式回归
will herald in the reemergence of our military,
并且给赫斯司令 足够的时间执行死灵计划
and provide Commandant Hux enough time to deliver on Project Necromancer.
裴里昂舰长 你的发言总是如此权威
Captain Pellaeon, you always speak with much authority,
但这次还是一样
and yet, I see,  once again,
你的代表团里没看见索龙元帅的身影
that Grand Admiral Thrawn is missing from your delegation.
能告诉我们他何时能参加影子议会吗
Any word on when he will be able to participate in the Shadow Council?
恕我直言 如果我们想成功 他的回归就必须保密
With respect, our one hope for success relies upon the secrecy of his return.
舰长 刺探秘密是我的专长
Captain, secrets are my stock-in-trade.
我能听见银河各角落的传闻
I hear whispers from one end of the galaxy to another,
却没听过索龙的消息
and never a word of Thrawn.
你老是说他即将回归
You have spoken of his imminent return.
或许这时我们也该指望新的领导
Perhaps, it's time we look to new leadership.
赞成
Hear, hear.
死灵计画已为此做好准备
Project Necromancer is in place for that.
是的 司令
Yes, Commandant.
珀欣博士在哪里  还有你答应过的研究呢
What has become of Doctor Pershing and the research you promised us?
珀欣博士被新共和国俘虏
Doctor Pershing was captured by the New Republic.
他的研究内容消失了
His research is lost.
至少目前是如此
For now, at least.
吉迪恩 我也听到传闻
I also hear whispers, Gideon.
听说珀欣在你手上 你自己还想在内瓦罗做实验
You held Pershing and were attempting your own experiments on Nevarro.
执着于生产复制人的是你 不是我
The creation of clones is your obsession, not mine.
我对我星区的事负责 不多也不少
I account for what goes on in my sector, no more, no less.
这话也适用于本议会所有成员
The same can be said of every member of this Council.
-是的 -当然
- Yes. - Of course.
-没错 -是的
- That's right. - Yes.
然而我们各自努力搜刮资源
And yet, we individually scrape and claw resources
等着宏大计画成形
awaiting the grand plan to take shape,
同时你和裴里昂却累积无数资源与设备
while you and Pellaeon amass countless resources
那些本该与大家共享
and equipment which should be shared.
我们已经收到你的请求
Oh, we already received your request.
「三名禁卫军」
"Three Praetorian Guards."
似乎有人担心会遭到刺杀
Sounds like someone is concerned about an assassination attempt.
那人还好意思觉得我浮夸
And he thinks I'm being the flashy one.
并且强化你的钛拦截机中队
And reinforcements for your TIE interceptor squadron.
还有...轰炸机
And... bombers.
我知道
Yes, I see.
你有什么安全顾虑
And what is your security concern?
曼达洛人
Mandalorians.
什么
What?
-他们仍然是问题吗  -是的
- They continue to be an issue? - They do.
我越来越坚信
I am increasingly confident
他们正准备收复家园曼达洛星
that they are preparing to retake their home world of Mandalore.
曼达洛的复兴有碍我们发展
A resurgent Mandalore would hamper our efforts.
所以我们必须立刻扫除他们
Which is why we need to stamp them out now.
没错
Yes.
我们会给你增援
You'll have your reinforcements.
还有护卫
And your guard.
我们将彻底铲除曼达洛人
We shall be rid of the Mandalorians once and for all.
帝国万岁
Long Live the Empire! Long Live the Empire!
曼达洛人
第三季第七集
本WEB版外挂字幕由  风吹来的那片云  双语合并
《第二十三章:探察者》
上太守 上太守
High Magistrate! High Magistrate!
一艘帝国穿梭机飞越城市上空
An Imperial shuttle is advancing over the city.
第一 那是轻型巡航舰 第二 那不是帝国的
First, that's a light cruiser. And second, it's not Imperial.
抱歉 长官 我的资料显示它是
With apologies, sir. According to my data, it is.
现在不是帝国的船了 你看那标志
No, no. It was an Imperial ship. Look at the markings.
朋友 他们是曼达洛民兵
See, those, my friend, are Mandalorian privateers.
我敢说那舰队有一半是从帝国抢来的
I'll bet you, half that fleet was captured from the Empire.
所以他们跟我们同一国
So, they're on our side then?
希望是这样
I should hope so.
我们去迎接客人 来吧
They're our welcomed guests. Come.
希望这两群人和睦相处
I hope these two groups get along.
他们没见过面
They've never met,
只知道彼此憎恶对方
and what little they know of each other, they hate.
他们想活就得和睦
They will if they wanna survive.
带孩子们进去
Take the children inside.
欢迎 曼达洛伙伴
Welcome, fellow Mandalorians.
我们邀请各位扎营
We invite you to make camp.
大家准备设宴款待客人
Let us prepare a feast for our guests.
老曼
Mando!
欢迎回来 我的朋友
Welcome back, my friend. Welcome back.
你召集的舰队真不赖
That's quite a fleet you've assembled.
一点小礼 欢迎我们的新邻居
Little welcome gift to celebrate our new neighbors.
来自远方的科罗森
That's all the way from Coruscant,
建议你等人少一点的时候再打开
so you might wanna wait for a smaller gathering before you open it.
-谢谢 -我还有别的礼物送你
- Thank you. - That's not the only gift I have for you.
你对IG-11做了什么
What did you do to IG-11?
他现在是IG-12 你喜欢他吗
No, that's IG-12 now. Do you like him?
我喜欢他吗
Do I like him?
别担心 他很安全
Don't worry. He's safe.
你确定
You're sure?
安泽人把IG拆到只剩基本机动功能
Well, the Anzellans stripped IG down to his base motor functions.
他们移除他的记忆体电路
They removed his memory circuit.
由驾驶来充当大脑
The pilot provides cognition.
是
Yes.
这样想吧 它更像是交通工具
Think of it this way. It's more like a vehicle. Hmm?
这样比较安全
It's safer that way.
坏宝宝 别挤
Bad baby. No squeezie!
他太小 不适合操控
Well, he's too little to operate this thing.
别急着否决 先试乘看看
No, no, no, no. Let's see if he fits.
你觉得呢
So what do you think?
我会说他们做得很好
They do nice work, I'll give them that.
但古古太小 不能操作重型机械
But, Grogu is too young to operate heavy machinery.
等他大一点吧
- Maybe when he's older.
不
No.
-什么叫「不」  -不
- What do you mean, "No?" No.
我猜他是说他够大 能操作了
I think he's sayin' he's old enough to operate it.
是
Yes.
-拎他出来 -不
- Get him out of there. - No.
至少让他在我办公室试驾
No, at least let him try it out in my office.
是
Yes.
不 这主意不好 出来
No, this is not a good idea. Come on.
你看到没
Will you look at that?
是
Yes.
「是」什么
"Yes" what?
是...是
- Yes. Yes. Yes. Yes. Yes. Yes. Yes. Yes.
你做什么
What are you doing?
住手 古古 不行 那要付钱的
Stop, Grogu. No. You have to pay for those.
-不行 古古 -是 不
- No. Hey. Grogu. - Yes. No.
-拿来 -不
- Give it. - No.
古古 还回去...
- Grogu, give it ba...
给你
Here.
我认为这行不通
This isn't working for me.
曼达洛人
BO-KATAN: Mandalorians.
收复我们家园的时候到了
It is time to retake our home world.
尽管星球没被诅咒 依然很危险
Even though the planet is not cursed, there are still dangers.
蛰伏的种族被轰炸唤醒
Dormant species have been awakened from the bombings.
残余的磁干扰
The remaining magnetic interference
导致无法从大气层上方扫描地表
has made it impossible to scan the surface from above atmosphere.
所以我提议我们离开内瓦罗
Which is why I'm proposing that we leave Nevarro
带舰队进入曼达洛星上方的轨道
and move the fleet into orbit above Mandalore.
我们派小型侦察队下去
We send down a small recon party.
搜索地表
We'll scout the surface,
找出大锻造厂的遗迹 建立安全阵地
find out what remains of the Great Forge, and establish a safe perimeter.
然后才能带其他人下去
Only then, will we bring down the others.
我需要包含两部族的自愿者
I need volunteers from both tribes.
我愿意去
I will go.
还有古古
Grogu as well.
我愿意去
I will go.
-我愿意去 -我愿意去
- I will go. - I will go.
我也愿意去
I will go as well.
派出侦察队到地表
Scouting party descending to surface.
通讯很快就会中断
We'll lose comms shortly.
比我想得还糟
It's worse than I thought.
事发时我在现场
I was here when it happened.
他们准备好了
They're ready.
确保渗透区安全
Secure infil zone.
手甲战机 降落区安全
Gauntlet, landing zone secure.
下面某处是我们以前的古老都城
Somewhere below is where our ancient capital once stood.
先探勘地表 找到锻造厂并建立安全区
We'll survey the surface until we find the Forge and create a safety zone.
然后才能带其他人下来定居
Only then will we begin to bring down the settlers.
从那个方向开始侦察
We start scouting in that direction.
列队
Form up.
那边 地平线上
There, on the horizon.
夜鸮
Nite Owls.
左侧加强
Flanking left.
你们有吃的吗
Do you have food?
有的
We do.
你穿戴夜鸮纹饰的盔甲
You wear the crest of the Nite Owls?
我希望是的
I should hope so.
他们是曼达洛人
They're Mandalorians.
那是布卡坦奎兹小姐的声音
Is that the voice of Lady Bo-Katan Kryze?
是的
It is.
你果然没抛弃我们 布卡坦小姐
We knew you would not forsake us, Lady Bo-Katan.
我们辜负了你 但我们依然会为你奋战
We have failed you, but our blasters remain in your service.
他们看到有飞船离开就拦下
They intercepted any ships they saw leaving.
他们不留俘虏
They took no prisoners.
他们把全地表轰炸了两轮
They bombed every surface twice over.
他们惩罚我们 用来警告全银河
They punished us as a warning to the whole galaxy
因为我们拒绝投降
because we refused to surrender.
不对
That's not true.
我当时投降了
I did surrender.
我们的部队在千泪之夜被歼灭后
After our forces were annihilated in the Night of a Thousand Tears
眼看大势已去
and defeat was imminent,
我见了吉迪恩星区长
I met with Moff Gideon.
帝防局联络我 说要协议停火
The ISB had reached out to me to negotiate a cease-fire.
只要屈服于帝国且放下武器
In exchange for submitting to the Empire and disarming,
就饶了剩余的城市与曼达洛人
all remaining cities and Mandalorian lives were to be spared.
因此吉迪恩星区长才得到黑剑
That is how Moff Gideon came to possess the Darksaber.
我不信任他
I didn't trust him,
但那是我挽救同胞唯一的机会
but it was the only chance I had to save our people.
他却背信弃义
And then he betrayed me
我们也无力抵抗曼达洛大肃清了
and we were helpless to resist the Purge of Mandalore.
这些人是如何生存的
How did these others survive?
我们躲藏在康果狄亚卫星
We were hidden on the moon of Concordia.
你们是死神护卫
Are you Death Watch?
死神护卫不存在了
Death Watch exists no longer.
分裂成许多派互相交战
It shattered into many warring factions.
我们的同胞反复受难
Our people have suffered time and again.
因为分裂与派系之争
From division and squabbling factions.
曼达洛星一向十分强大 从无敌手
Mandalore has always been too powerful for any enemy to defeat.
往往是内部的分裂把我们给毁了
It is always our own division that destroys us.
我本来不知道
I had no idea.
我们学到的是只剩我们没背弃正道
We were taught that everyone but us had forsaken the Way.
还有你们很自私且不在乎
That you were selfish and uncaring.
现在我明白了
Now I understand.
你说得对
You were right.
我是很自私
I was selfish.
造成了这种结果
And this is what it wrought.
我们会重建
We'll rebuild it.
就像我们的历史
Isn't that our history?
数千年来 我们一直濒临灭绝
For thousands of years, we have been on the verge of extinction,
而数千年来 我们都存活着
and for thousands of years, we have survived.
我不确定我能否让大家齐心
I don't know if I can keep everyone together.
太多仇恨了
There's too much animosity.
这把剑是我团结人民的唯一倚仗
And this blade is all I have to unify our people.
我是听你说才知道这把武器
I only know of this weapon what you taught me.
老实说我们那派没当它是一回事
To be honest, it means nothing to me or my people.
身分和血统也不重要
Nor does station or bloodline.
我更看重的是荣誉
What means more to me is honor.
还有忠诚与人格
And loyalty. And character.
我是因此才为你效力 奎兹小姐
These are the reasons I serve you, Lady Kryze.
你的歌谣还没写成
Your song is not yet written.
在此之前 我都供你差遣
I will serve you until it is.
今晚休息 天一亮再继续
We'll rest tonight and continue at first light.
这些人太虚弱 无法参与
These here are too weak to continue.
必须返回手甲战机
We must return to the Gauntlet
明天我会送他们回舰队
and I will ferry them back to the fleet in the morning.
同意
Agreed.
队长
Captain?
你们体力够的
Those of you who are well enough
就一起来找大锻造厂
can join us in the search for the Great Forge.
有更好的办法
We can do better than that.
直接带你们过去
We can bring you there.
前进 曼达洛人 前往锻造厂
Onward, Mandalorians! To the Forge!
执行者不能这样走
You can't move an Enforcer like that.
那是侧跳 你准备屈服吧
It's a flank jump. And you're about to submit.
但只有翔卫可以侧跳
But only the Wing Guard can flank jump.
执行者在两侧的移动比照翔卫
The Enforcer moves like a Wing Guard when it's flanking.
这些原始人什么规则都自己编造
These primitives make up their own rules for everything.
认真的吗
Seriously?
屈服或战斗
Submit or fight.
你敢相信吗
Can you believe this?
我该插手吗
Should I step in?
两边都无法插手
Neither side can step in.
迟早都会起冲突的
It was bound to happen sooner or later.
不...不
No. No. No. No. No. No. No.
你教的好徒儿
You taught your apprentice well.
那不是跟我学的
He didn't learn that from me.
呼叫舰队指挥部
Come in, Fleet Command.
请说
We read you.
准备收置获救的幸存者 他们需要医护
Prepare to receive rescued survivors in need of medical attention.
收到 手甲战机
Copy, Gauntlet.
那边 在右舷前方
There, on the starboard bow!
弃船
Abandon ship!
我们走
Let's go!
这边 这边
This way! This way!
赶快 快点
Hurry up! Faster!
还行吗
You good?
不远了 还要再往下
We're not far. We need to go further down.
走...走
Go, go, go.
Go! Go, go!
这是哪里
Where are we?
这是大锻造厂的残骸
This is what's left of the Great Forge.
这曾是我们文明的核心
This was once the heart of our civilization.
但自从轰炸之后 火就熄了
But the fires have been extinguished since the bombings.
你住在这里
You lived here?
我们都是
We all did.
我们没离开
We never left.
沿着地表迁徙求生 直到战争结束
Survived by migrating along the surface until the war ended.
有人往下探索 但没人生还
Some tried to explore below, but none survived.
喷射背包
Jet packs?
其他幸存者
More survivors?
他们不是曼达洛人
Those aren't Mandalorians.
-是帝国的人 -找掩护
They're Imperials! Take cover.
他们身穿贝斯卡装甲
They're wearing beskar armor!
我们被包围了 需要支援
We're pinned down. We need backup.
我可以前往舰队带援军过来
I can make a run for the fleet and get us reinforcements.
不 太远了
No, it's too far.
我行的 为了收复星球必须一搏
I can make it. It's our only shot at taking the planet back.
那边天花板有裂缝
There's a split in the ceiling there.
我掩护你
I'll lay down cover.
他们撤退了
They're retreating!
-前进 -为了曼达洛
Advance. For Mandalore!
孩子 你要跟上
Okay, kid. You've gotta keep up.
这是什么地方
What is this place?
有埋伏
It's an ambush.
没收他的武器
Disarm him.
多亏你将曼达洛人聚在一处
Thank you for gathering the Mandalorians into one place.
你们很有本事 但你们的时代结束了
You were a talented people, but your time has passed.
不过 如你所见 曼达洛星将由我统治
However, as you can see, Mandalore will live on in me.
多亏这星球的丰富资源
Thanks to your planet's rich resources,
我打造了新一代的黑暗兵装甲
I have created the next generation Dark Trooper suit
以贝斯卡合金锻造
forged from beskar alloy.
最优异的改进之处就是将我放在里面
And the most impressive improvement is that it has me in it.
每个社群都能有所贡献
You see, every society has something to offer.
复制科学家 绝地
The cloners. The Jedi.
连曼达洛人也不例外
And even the Mandalorians.
透过结合各家所长
By aggregating the best of each,
我创造出的军队将足以恢复银河秩序
I will create an army that will bring order to the galaxy.
我要歼灭你们的舰队
Why don't we take your fleet off the board
趁现在发动奇袭
while we still have the element of surprise.
派出拦截机和轰炸机
Activate the interceptors and bombers.
不
No!
不用多久 曼达洛大肃清就能彻底完成
In but a few moments, the Purge of Mandalore will be complete.
带他到汇报室
Take him to the debriefing room.
我早该把握机会杀了你
I should have killed you when I had the chance.
布卡坦
Bo-Katan.
下次别再像这样见面
We have to stop meeting like this.
不会再有下次
I'll make sure of it.
我们就闲话少说了
Let's skip the pleasantries, shall we?
我认为这时候
I believe this is the part
你该将黑剑交还原主
where you return the Darksaber to its rightful owner.
现在 交出黑剑
Now, surrender the Darksaber,
告诉他们这星球是我的
and tell these people that this planet is mine.
我辈之道
This is the Way.
打开防爆门
Open the blast doors.
杀了他们
Kill them.
-走吧 -快走
Move out! Move out!
撤退 我掩护后方
Fall back! I'll cover the rear!
快走
Go, go, go! Go! Go, go, go, go!
可以走了 撤退
We're clear. Fall back.
快来 我们不会丢下你
Come on. We're not leaving you behind.
走吧 太多了
Go. There are too many.
不
No!
我辈之道
This is the Way.
字幕翻译:简芝桦